# **ANITHA NANCY**

Email: jtsnancy@gmail.com

Mobile: 9962914041

## **Career Objective:**

Obtain to work in an organization demanded all my skills to explore and realize the potential to accomplish the growth of the company with an impressive performance.

### **Professional Summary:**

I started my career as a graduate trainee in the Investment banking sector handling Mutual Fund accounting operations and NAV calculations, then moved as Analyst in Alternative Investment Services and products operations, In middle office operations worked as Senior Analyst in Rates, options and swaptions products, Getting trained and certified as Business Analyst with BA Centric Solutions and worked on small projects.

#### **Academic Qualification:**

- ➤ MBA Finance Loyola College (PULC) (2015 -2017) 76% aggregate
- > BCom General Meenakshi College for women (2011 2014) 79% aggregate
- ➤ HSS TLGHSS School (2009 2011) 84% aggregate
- ➤ SSLC TLGHSS School (2005 2009) 80% aggregate

#### **Skill Set**

- UML Modelling Tools: Draw.io/ MS Visio 2010
- Modelling Language: UML 2.0 (CF flowchart)
- Testing: Manual Testing
- Project Management Tool: JIRA
- Prototyping tools: Balsamiq 2.0, wireframes, lucid charts
- Preparing Business Requirement documents
- Maintains Income and expenses statement and prepare Financial Statements.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

As a Business Analyst I worked on the project like preparing Business requirement documentation, Functional Requirement documentation, and preparing wireframes to show mock up screens, Catchup meeting with stake holders to discuss about the product or requirements, performing research, analysing and coming with solution to the clients. Tracks the company's income and expenses to maintain in the positive growth. Over the period I got trained and certified as Advanced Business Analysis (Certification ID: BACSHYD/1903216) and doing projects.

# Individual Contributor/ Senior Analyst BARCLAYS (P) ltd (April 2020 – April 2021)

Barclays is a British multinational investment bank and financial service company. As a senior analyst, my core activities include

- Analysing and documenting Business and Functional requirements for multiple clienteles.
- Researching and Analysing the findings to suggest on the business decisions
- Involved in project management activities like project scoping, planning, estimation, scheduling, organizing and controlling
- Skilled in identifying and documenting quality user business requirements for new product implementation and major enhancements

- Work with business personnel to ascertain requirement changes and interface the required changes to design and development teams and other stake holders.
- Analyse business problems and provide solutions to users/ clients
- Experience in working tools like Draw.io/MS Viso, Balsamiq and RTM
- Competent in MS office, Business and Functional Requirement Document
- Conduct requirement gathering meetings with the teams to explore solutions.
- Familiarity in activities that consist of sprint planning, sprint demo, sprint retrospective and daily stand-up meetings.
- Responsible for supplying expiry reports to the trader on a daily and weekly basis.
- Work with SDLC (software development life cycle) according to client specific and perform in the role of UAT test plans, host daily status calls.
- Instruments were worked on like interest rates, swaption, option etc.
- Work with balsamiq to ease the discussion and understanding of the project.
- Validating the expiry trades on the notice date and supplying the results to the counterparty.
- Exposure in JIRA, Tracking support issues/tasks/bugs and in user stories, use cases
- Uploading the term sheet or initial document of the trades in SharePoint to the traders for the required period.
- According to the decision of the trader, the expiry results were prepared and produced to the counterparty.
- Understanding of System Requirement Specification, Requirements Traceability Matrix and User Acceptance Testing
- Ensuring the rates are booked as per the document and checking the interest rates are booked correctly.
- Verifying the notice data falls on the working days, (In case of any holidays may affect the notice date).
- Checking on any discontinuation of libor tenor for the books.
- ◆ Application worked on Summit (Trades booked through the trade blotter)
- ◆ Swerve (storage of trade details to generate as report)
- ♦ TIES (extraction trade details)
- ◆ Exotic Desktop (verifying trade ID and deal ID)

## Done Projects with BA Centric Solutions / COEPD (Nov 2022 – Till now)

**BACentric Solutions** is a service driven company specialising in project management, business analyst training and business continuity management serving across the world.

## **COEPD – Center of Excellence for Professional Development**

It is a primarily a community of Institute for Business Analysts, which provides training to the Aspirants and be a part of service driven to companies The objective of COEPD is to minimize project failures by contributing in the areas of Business Analysis.

Here I do work on project likes preparing documents; create use case documents using visio and Balasmiq and good exposure in JIRA application as well.

## Fund Administrator/ Analyst BNY MELLON (P) ltd (Nov 2017 – July 2019)

BNY Mellon was formed from the merger of The Bank of New York and the Mellon Financial Corporation in 2007. It is the world's largest custodian bank and securities services company.

- Reconciliation includes various instruments like Bank Debts, Term Loan, and Delayed Draw Term Loan etc.
- Performing cash reconciliation between Client reports, Broker report and Custodian (Geneva) for private equity funds.
- Ensuring all trades is uploaded accurately in Geneva application into appropriate client portfolios daily.
- Verifying all income/expenses is accurately booked into the appropriate client portfolios

- Ensured interest are generating on the precise basis as shown in the AIS portfolio system are reconciled to the client report or to the Prime Broker statement
- Posting expenses accrual entries in Geneva
- Received a BRAVO award for arduous work and connect the dots within a Year.

Fund NAV Analyst & Sales support Analyst FRANKLIN TEMPLETON INV (May 2014 – Dec 2016)
Franklin Templeton, Inc. is an American multinational company holding its subsidiaries in a globally to delivering exceptional asset management for Institutional, retail and high net worth clients.

- The Fund accounting process includes Accounting of Trades settlements, Dividend cycle, Income and expenses accrual, Corporate Actions, posting Journal entries which will be instructed by the GFAR team and calculation of NAV.
- Calculating Net Asset value for our own Mutual Funds.
- Prepare prompt and exact Net Asset Value, yields, Distributions and other Fund accounting output.
- Record Accurately by the accounting records as securities position, corporate actions and journal entries which are instructed by other services teams.
- Review the corporate actions which are processed/ noticed by corporate action team and posting various entries received from another services team.
- Reconcile various accounts or review reconciliations prepared by others and promptly research and correct any variances.
- Identifying exceptions and problems affecting accounting records and prices, communicating same to management and aiding in their resolution.
- Exposure to various market products like Equities, Bonds, Swaps, Futures and options etc.
- Preliminary Justification of Income and Expenses.
- Reviewing NAV before releasing
- Maintain and complete all monthly scheduled reports using defined procedures by the prescribed deadline
- Exposure in Fund of Funds, High profile funds, OEIC (International funds) and Money market funds etc.
- Perform co-ordination of periodic audit reports of requirements like payment in Kind (PIK), Treasury Inflation Protected Security (TIPS)
- Worked in International fund Hedging Task and Month end packs

## **Certifications and awards:**

- I have played a significant role in enhancement and received TAKE A BOW award for demanding work within fleeting time and in attrition period.
- **Applause award** in creating MACRO to pull reports for Month end task. Specific appreciation mail from client.
- Completion of Advanced Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt certification (Unique Certificate Code SG2022YB0012693)
- Certificate of completion on Advanced Business Analysis (Certification ID: BACSHYD/1903216)

## **Personal Skills**

- Dedication and commitment towards finding solutions to problems.
- Good motivator, enthusiastic and come up with innovative ideas.
- Possess good verbal and written communication skills.
- Quick learner, adaptable and flexible in tough situations.
- ❖ Ability to handle multiple tasks.

## **Personal Information**

D.O.B: 10 June 1994 Gender: Female Marital Status: Married

Location: Chennai (Purasaiwakkam)